Contact

haydal.tmps@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/david-hayden-39893b41 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Traffic Engineering
Civil Engineering
AutoCAD

David Hayden

Freelance TTM (Temporary Traffic Management) Consultant / Designer (AU & NZ) based in Ireland.

Summary

Traffic & Transportation Engineer,
Specialist in Traffic Management Planning / Design for Australia
(VIC) & New Zealand

Level 2/3 NP COPTTM Qual'd (New Zealand)
RIICWD503A - "Workzone Traffic Management Planning (Australia)

VicRoads Accredited "Road Safety Auditor" specialising in Construction Traffic Management Planning

BEng Civil & Transportation Engineering (Hons) (Napier University)

Freelance work capable.

Experience

David Hayden

Ireland

Freelance Traffic Management Consultant / Designer (AU & NZ) January 2016 - Present

Freelance Traffic Engineer, specialising in Temporary Traffic Management Planning for Construction & Events, primarily in Australia (VIC) & New Zealand (Auckland & Waikato Regions).

Specialist in Vehicle Swept Path Analysis for Construction Sites, and New Developments.

Currently working remotely from County Kerry, Ireland.

Chevron Traffic Services
TMP & Corridor Access Request (CAR) Consultant
May 2012 - December 2016 (4 years 8 months)

Design & drafting of Traffic Management Plans for civil works of varying sizes for various contractors, submitting proposals to Road Controlling Authorities (RCA's) for approval. Liaising with clients and contractors re current and future work on a daily basis.

Filcon Safety Group Senior Traffic Management Planner March 2014 - May 2015 (1 year 3 months)

Filcon Safety Group
Traffic Management Planner
June 2013 - March 2014 (10 months)

Design and drafting Traffic Management Plans for various sized Construction Sites around the Melbourne area. Worked as part of a team of 3. Attended onsite meetings with Project Managers when required. Dealt with clients/ PM's on a daily basis, discussing variations to existing plans, or developing new plans for upcoming sites. Met clients onsite myself, to discuss the project, clients needs, conduct a site investigation, etc.

Moreland City Council
Transport Engineer
January 2012 - March 2012 (3 months)

Short term contract role, providing Traffic and Transportation advice, support and preparation of plans on AutoCAD for traffic related matters including LATM works, Parking Restriction Implementation, Stakeholder Consultation, processing of Council Road Closure Permits and reviewing Traffic Management Plans for proposed works on Council Roads.

Manningham City Council
Traffic and Transport Engineer
March 2011 - November 2011 (9 months)

- Collecting of traffic data for the preparation of strategies for traffic and other relevant technical issues.
- Preparing plans on AutoCAD for traffic related matter including local traffic management works and parking restriction implementation.
- Assessing Traffic Management Plans and Memorandum of Authorisation requests, liaise with applicants to finalise required amendments and make recommendations for approval of plans.

- Undertaking investigations, and assisting with the preparation of technical reports for presentation to Council, and the unit's customers on various matters relevant to traffic.
- Assisting with the development approvals function and provide traffic advice on development proposals, and road authority approvals
- Developing traffic management proposals for identified traffic problems to concept stage.
- Attending meetings with the Team Leader / Manager to provide technical support and advice for clients.

Malachy Walsh and Partners
Engineering Technician / Junior Engineer
November 2006 - August 2008 (1 year 10 months)
Cork, Ireland

Engineering Technician Role (November 2006 - August 2007)

Junior Engineer Role within the Traffic and Transportation Department of Malachy Walsh and Partners (June 2008 - September 2008)

These roles involved:

- General AutoCAD drafting for the Senior Engineers, ranging from fire certificate drawings, to concept designs, to site development plans for the site engineers drainage, site layout, etc.
- Preparing plans on AutoCAD for traffic engineering related solutions, for the Traffic and Transportation Engineers this included using AutoCAD extension software AutoTRACK Vehicular Swept Path Analysis.
- Preparation of documents for the Traffic and Transportation Engineers including Traffic Impact Assessments, Road Safety Audits, Parking Survey Reports and on-site Speed Survey Reports.
- Attending meetings with the Team Leader / Manager to provide technical support and advice for clients.
- Undertaking various Traffic Surveys, including Parking Surveys, Traffic Counts and Speed Surveys on behalf of Malachy Walsh and Partners.

Education

Edinburgh Napier University
BEng Hons Degree, Civil and Transportation · (2007 - 2009)

Cork Institute of Technology
BEng Ord Degree, Civil Engineeing · (2003 - 2006)